Sebastián Cantergiani

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/s-cantergiani

Location: Santiago, Chile Portfolio: scantergiani.github.io Mobile: +56-9-9699-5790

Professional Summary

A Business Administrator with a specialization in Economics and Finance. Over 2 years of experience in entrepreneurship and project development, currently committed to the business intelligence and data analytics field. Resilient, autonomous, determined, with a focus on making informed decisions. Great analytical thinker, proficiency in storytelling, and detail-oriented. With a high interest in performing in the data analysis area.

EDUCATION

Universidad Adolfo Ibañez

Santiago, Chile May. 2023 - Present

Email: sebastiancantergiani@gmail.com

Data Analysis Diploma

Universidad Andrés Bello

Santiago, Chile

B.S. in Business Administration with specialization in Economics and Finance.

Mar. 2015 - Dic. 2019

TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS

- SQL: Perform queries in BigQuery and PostgreSQL, Sort and filter data using queries such as where, group by and order by, Convert data types using functions, Merge tables using join statements.
- Python: Create programs capable of reading and creating data from files, Extract data from websites and APIs, Pandas data wrangling , Manage databases using SQLite, etc.
- R: Install and use the tidyverse package in R, Run scripts in RStudio, Create data visualizations in RStudio, Create reports in R Markdown.
- Power BI: Create data visualizations and dashboards, Import, sort, and clean data using Power Query, Model and relate data tables, Use basic DAX for measures and calculated columns.
- Tableau: Create data visualization, reports and dashboards.
- Excel: Perform calculations using functions, Import, sort and clean data in Power Query, Pivot table management, Create relationships using functions such as vlookup, Use VBA for macros and user forms, Create data visualization.

EXPERIENCIA

Inversiones Imola Jr Proyect Manager

Santiago, Chile

Sep 2021 - Jan 2023

 Provided financial consulting, budget management, negotiated with suppliers, and oversaw the execution of key project phases such as preliminary design, building permits, construction, etc.

Entrepreneurship

Santiago, Chile

CEO

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

o In charge of the production, distribution and commercialization of Kefir based products. Develop an e-commerce solution through WooCommerce. Also responsible for introducing the product in multiple stores.

Naturaterra Propiedades

Santiago, Chile

Jr Financial Analyst

Dic 2019 - Aug 2020

• Financial statement analysis of the company. Recommends a change in fixed costs and incentives for workers, enabling a transition from losses to profits.

Universidad Andrés Bello

Santiago, Chile

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

Assistant to 2 distinguished academics to teach fundamentals of economics.

Projects

- Google Fiber Business Inteligence Project: Case study focused on project planning, data preparation (ETL), and dashboard design.
- Portal Inmobiliario Web Scraping: Extract and organize public real estate information automatically through web-scraping. Utilize data analysis tools to obtain relevant information.
- Google Data Analytics Capstone Project: Analyze and identify trends and patterns among customer segments through problem identification, data preparation, data cleaning, analysis, data visualization, and recommendations.

CERTIFICATES

Coursera Coursera

Google Business Inteligence Professional Certificate.

Apr. 2023 - Apr. 2023

Coursera

Coursera Feb. 2023 - Mar. 2023

Python for Everybody Specialization by University of Michigan.

Coursera Jan. 2023 - Mar. 2023

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate.

COMMUNICATION

Coursera

• Languages: Native Spanish, Advanced English, Intermediate Portuguese.